Celina Palmer-Belcher

Charleston, SC | 843-367-8876 | cpalmerbelcher@gmail.com Portfolio |Linkedin

JOB TITLE

Creative and dynamic front end junior developer with a background in graphic design and over 10 years of customer service experience. Looking to partner up with an organization that values creativity, teamwork, and the ability to continuously learn and grow.

SKILLS

Software: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, React, Office suites, Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop Leadership: self-motivated, problem solver, team player, logistics, project management, communication

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

JavaScript Application (Pokédex) - Github | Demo

An application where the user is able to view a list of data and see more details for a given data item on demand.

- A small web application built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript that loads data from an external API and enables the viewing of data points in detail
- Created an aesthetically pleasing and easy to use application using CSS
- Loads data from an external API via fetch
- Displays a list of items with on user action (e.g., by clicking on a list item), viewing details for that item

Meet App - Github | Demo

This application uses the Google Calendar API to fetch upcoming events for the user.

- Built a serverless, progressive web application (PWA) with React using a test-driven development (TDD)
- Uses Google Calendar API to fetch upcoming events
- Combines Serverless and PWAs
- Using a TDD approach, I wrote the tests before writing the actual functionality for the app in code

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Logistics Coordinator

Charleston, South Carolina

BNSF Logistics

2017 - Present

- Oversees around 4 major clients projects and their supply needs, coordinating shipments for transportation and
- Investigates any shipment issues as they arise and processes freight claims for billing

Creative Coordinator

Charleston, South Carolina

2011 - 2013

CreateSpace, An Amazon Company

- Ensured that projects were on schedule, liaising with vendors, and processing expenditures for clients
- Coordinated with team members to develop a strong understanding of the scope and expectations of each

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Customer Service/Server

Wild Dunes Resort

Charleston, South Carolina

2010 - 2017

- Specialized in guest management throughout the resort, moving within each department for support and
- Improved customer relationships by handling questions and concerns with speed and professionalism

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree, The Art Institute of Charleston Graphic Design

Charleston, SC 2008-2011

Certificate, CareerFoundry

Online

Full Stack Web Development

2021-2022